(Watch on KonFlix.vip)
[A Splendid Match]
[Episode 16]
It's all my fault.
Are there any
songs you want to hear?
Anything is fine.
The one thing this post station
doesn't lack
is a broken heart.
[Ji's Depot in Tongzhou]
Come, put it over here.
I see Miss Gu
working at the depot every day recently.
She's truly exhausted.
It's good to be busy.
It leaves less time to worry.
Over here.
I wonder
if the water transport is open yet.
No way. It's completely silted up.
A large canal ship with a carrying capacity
of 55,000 kilograms
can't get through at all.
The only option is to go by land.
What should we do then?
If grain prices keep rising,
how are we supposed to survive?
It doesn't matter if we survive or not.
The real problem is
the Nine Border Garrisons.
If war breaks out
and the soldiers have no rations,
that's when we're truly done for.
I've heard that in Shanxi,
the drought is still ongoing.
Third Master,
I just received news.
The grain transport team
is not far from Tongzhou.
You guessed it right.
They...
They did use the Ji family's fleet.
They are counting on
my relationship with the Ji family,
thinking that even if I find out,
I won't dare to say anything.
Stick to the original plan.
Follow them closely,
but don't alert them.
Yes.
Hello, Second Master.
Second Cousin,
I thought you were in Sanhe.
Why are you back?
The grain transport team
is arriving today.
Of course I have to be here.
Yao.
Every time I come to the depot,
I see you here.
As a girl,
aren't you afraid of getting a tan?
I don't lack jewelry.
It's not jewelry.
It's your favorite scallion-shaped candy.
Thank goodness.
You finally smiled.
I heard from Uncle Ping.
You sent men to investigate
shops in Shanxi.
Since when
are you interested in Shanxi?
Since you're here,
please keep an eye on things for me.
I want to go out for a walk
and get some fresh air.
-Zhao.
-The grain carts are here!
The grain carts are finally here.
They're here.
The grain carts are here!
Let's go.
[Good weather for the crops]
The grain carts are here.
Get ready to unload.
[Ji's Depot]
Count all the grain first.
Everyone...
[Ji]
Use your previous vouchers
to claim your pre-ordered goods.
Pay the silver,
and get the grain.
I know what you are worried about.
Our master said
prices won't increase by a single cent.
That's good.
[Ji]
The Ji family is righteous and kind!
Unload! Unload!
Okay.
-Unload!
-Unload! Unload!
[Ji]
Hurry up! Be quick!
Hurry up!
Why does that guy look somewhat familiar?
They look a bit like those bandits
from the Southwest.
Are you sure?
I've played with them in a gambling house.
It seems like it's them.
What should we do?
[Ji]
This grain cart is headed to Miyun.
Go ahead.
Please stop causing trouble!
My sister clearly told you.
She is going to transport
half of the grain here to the capital.
Why are you intercepting it?
Why?
Because the grain shops in the capital
are offering too low a price.
Do you know
how much effort I put
into collecting this grain?
I don't care.
I only listen to my sister.
You guys, those things...
Get up.
Fine.
I won't argue with you.
Let's go ask Grandmother to judge.
Judge? Let's go then!
Let's go.
It seems they also noticed
that something is wrong.
This commotion
might alert them.
Those guys are desperadoes.
The Ji family might be in danger.
Here's the plan.
You take some men
and continue following the grain carts.
I'll go check things out.
I saw it clearly.
They are those bandits from the Southwest.
And what's in those sacks
is definitely not rice.
It's swords.
What should we do?
It seems they want
to use our grain transport team
to smuggle weapons into the capital.
Illegally transporting weapons
is a serious crime.
Listen, Rong.
Go inform Zhao.
Tell her the situation here.
She should have a way
to find Third Master.
I'll try to keep these bandits distracted.
And I'll send someone to Tongzhou Guard
to gather some men
and surround the depot from the outside.
Anyway, no matter what,
we must not let these weapons
leave our depot.
Okay.
I'll go right now.
Go.
Give me one.
Zhao!
The goods are problematic!
Go find Third Master!
I told you.
It's useless to capture me.
Move.
You want to use me
to blackmail Chen Yanyun,
don't you?
Move!
You're mistaken.
Our Ji family
are merely servants to the Chen family.
Throughout history,
servants die for their masters.
When have you ever seen
a master die for a servant?
Am I right?
Otherwise...
Why did you come to kidnap me?
Why didn't your master come?
Why are you so talkative?
Move!
Using me
won't get you leverage over Chen Yanyun,
and it will cost you your life.
Instead of losing both wealth
and your life,
why don't we
have a proper negotiation?
Shut up! Move!
Stop right there!
Don't come any closer,
or I'll kill her!
Let her go!
Let her go
and you might still have a chance to live.
I am the one you want to deal with.
Let her go
and I will come with you.
Go over there!
Behind you is a cliff.
You have no way out.
Let her go.
My life is worth more than hers.
I wouldn't have guessed
that a civil official like you
actually had some guts.
Let her go.
Throw your sword over!
Third Master.
Don't worry about me!
Hurry up!
Step back!
Further back!
Don't move!
Don't try any tricks!
Don't hurt her!
Jinzhao!
Hold me tight.
Jinzhao,
are you alright?
I think I sprained my ankle.
Any other
discomfort?
No, just my ankle.
Third Master, are you alright?
This cliff isn't high,
and the soil is soft.
I'm fine.
Let me take a look.
Ouch.
Luckily it's not dislocated.
A tendon is pulled.
I can massage it back,
but it might hurt a bit.
Can you bear it?
Feeling a bit better?
Much better.
It's nothing serious.
It should be fine by tomorrow.
But you can't walk too far yet.
Even though it's not very deep,
we can't get back up from here either.
No hurry.
It's not dark yet.
Jiang Yan and the others
will find us here soon enough.
What are you doing?
You'll know in a minute.
Later,
Jiang Yan and the others
will see the smoke and find us here.
What are you looking at now?
You have already
saved me many times.
Actually, this time,
it was me who dragged you into this.
They are mainly after me.
Rong said
the goods were problematic.
Could that
be connected to them as well?
They wanted to use
my relationship with the Ji family
to smuggle the weapons out.
So that's how it is.
You look
a bit different
from two months ago.
Why?
You don't talk as much,
and you smile
less too.
I really feel much better.
That's good.
I heard
that you bought
a lot of properties in Shanxi
and invested in a large draft bank.
I didn't mean to investigate you.
It's just that...
Large draft banks in Shanxi
are tied to the nation's
grain and finances.
So the Court decrees
that any change in share capital
must
be reported to the authorities.
Why did you suddenly
become interested in Shanxi?
I've just been
thinking these days
about where my future lies.
I've thought it over
and decided that Shanxi
might be the most suitable place for me.
You're not thinking of...?
I plan to remain unmarried in the future
and go to Shanxi
to manage businesses.
Because of your mother?
Yes,
partly
because of my mother.
But
not entirely.
Sages all say that
the key to marriage
lies in mutual suitability.
This means that marriage
should be good for both parties.
That's the principle.
But when it comes to myself,
I really can't think of
any benefits
marriage would bring me.
So
I've decided
not to take that risk.
I'm sorry.
I really shouldn't
be telling you this.
I've never thought about
what you just said.
I don't know how to answer.
But your reasoning is sound.
One
should only do things
that have some benefit.
Then...
When are you going to Shanxi?
I haven't decided yet.
But...
If I go,
it will be after I've seen out
my grandmother's final years.
-My Lady!
-Third Master!
-Zhao!
-My Lady!
Zhao!
-Third Master!
-My Lady!
Third Master!
-Zhao!
-My Lady!
What should we do?
Third Master!
It's only been a short while.
How did something so big happen?
Look!
There's smoke over there!
Let's go!
Let's go.
Go, go, go.
Third Master,
is he dead?
He wasn't as lucky as we were.
We had leaves to cushion our fall.
But he hit this rock
and that killed him.
Third Master,
look inside the robes on his chest.
Is there something there?
Banknotes.
[Great Yan Bank
General Circulation Banknotes]
Xinlong Bank, Guiyang Branch.
There's also a letter.
[The Ji family's merchant fleet
can be used]
These bandits
really had a plan all along.
It seems they've had their eyes
on your Ji family from the start.
May I see it?
[The Ji family's merchant fleet
can be used]
My Lady.
Here's a new prescription
from Divine Doctor Xiao
[Astragalus 1 liang 8 qian,
Codonopsis 1 liang 5 qian]
[Poria 1 liang 5 qian,
Atractylodes 1 liang 2 qian]
[The Ji family's merchant fleet
can be used]
Miss Gu.
Jinzhao.
[The Ji family's merchant fleet
can be used]
This handwriting looks exactly the same
as Divine Doctor Xiao's.
He prescribed medicine for my mother.
You mean
the physician Ye Xian invited for you?
Yes.
His name is Xiao You.
He's Ye Xian's master.
Xiao You?
What does he look like?
High nose, narrow eyes,
and thin lips as blades.
Oh right,
he has a growth
on his left earlobe.
Just as I suspected.
No wonder I couldn't find him
no matter how hard I looked.
And here I was thinking
how to protect
Marquis Changxing's Mansion.
It seems he was hiding
right under our noses.
You have been looking for him?
Yes.
Xiao You is not his real name.
His real name is Xiao Qishan.
He was the most capable strategist
of the former Prince Chengqing's
residence.
But...
He is Ye Xian's master.
Doesn't that mean Ye Xian
and the entire Marquis Changxing's Mansion
will be implicated in this?
Yes.
Zhao!
Third Master!
Apart from people of the Ji Mansion,
all available constables and bailiffs
from the Tongzhou Prefectural Office
have gone out of the city to search.
Old Madam Ji has also paid a heavy sum
to hire experienced escort guards
from both the Weiyuan
and Fuyuan Escort Agencies
to help with the search.
Thankfully, it didn't take too long.
The bandits have all been caught.
They confessed
that they only had two leaders.
And they are from the Southwest.
The one who kidnapped Miss Gu
was one of them.
And these two leaders
take orders directly from Head Xiao.
As for the rest,
they are bandits recruited
along the way.
Did they confess
where these weapons
were supposed to go?
To Prince Ruichang's manor
in the suburbs of the capital.
Just as I expected.
Third Master,
about Xiao Qishan
hiding in Marquis Changxing's Mansion,
should we keep it a secret for now?
I spoke out of turn.
Oh, you said
only the two leaders
were their own men,
and the others were temporarily recruited?
Then find another group of men
and secretly
deliver these goods
to Prince Ruichang's manor.
Pretend nothing happened.
Can you do that?
It shouldn't be a problem.
We can do it discreetly.
I'll go make arrangements first.
Alright.
Why are you here?
Your foot is just getting better.
Walk slower.
Yes, I will.
Third Master,
I think Ye Xian
definitely doesn't know about Xiao You.
If he knew,
he would surely hide him
without hesitation.
How could he willingly
let him come treat my mother?
He must be kept in the dark.
That makes sense.
But
do you have any proof?
Even if Ye Xian is kept in the dark,
what about Marquis Changxing?
Does he know nothing either?
To be honest,
I actually
don't believe
that Marquis Changxing
would commit treason.
Because
Marquis Changxing and the former
Prince Chengqing
have a deep blood feud.
Back then,
when the former Prince Chengqing's
rebellion failed
and he was defeated in battle,
it was Marquis Changxing
who cut him down with one stroke
of his blade.
So that's what happened?
Therefore,
just one or two people
not believing it is not enough.
Xiao Qishan was protected
in Marquis Changxing's Mansion
for so many years,
and he is also Ye Xian's master.
Based on these two points alone,
Marquis Changxing
cannot escape involvement.
Then,
do you have any way to save them?
I don't have a way either.
I know you want to help Ye Xian,
but this is a very serious matter.
You,
me,
the Ji family,
and the Chen family...
If we get implicated,
the slightest carelessness
could mean total destruction.
Do you understand?
I understand.
Third Master, we can set off.
Let's go.
Then you
should head back soon.
Aren't you coming into the city?
I need to rush back to the capital.
Sister,
let's go back too.
I'm not going back.
Yao,
I have urgent business
and need to return to the capital.
Lend me two horses.
And as for grandmother,
find a way to cover for me
with her.
All right.
Then you
be very careful on the road.
Okay.
Give me that.
Hyah!
My Lady!
Acting behind Third Master
and sneaking back to the capital like this
to inform the Young Master Ye,
are we betraying Third Master?
No.
As long as it doesn't involve him,
or the entire Ji and Chen families,
it's fine.
Hyah!
[Ciqing Palace]
Ye Xian,
please sit.
I'm
not being alarmist.
Ever since my father fell seriously ill,
the palace has been in a state of unrest.
All sorts of shady characters
have come out of the woodwork.
Even I have heard it several times.
They say I am too young
to bear the weight of the throne
and my father should pass it
to Prince Ruichang.
Your Highness,
you trust me too much.
If I can't even tell
whether you are loyal or treacherous,
then I would truly be as those people say.
"Can't bear the weight of the throne."
I know
that your Marquis Changxing's family
are all incredibly loyal.
Mother has said this
several times.
Mr. Chen also said it.
Lord Chen also said it?
Yes.
Mr. Chen said that
among all the military nobility,
Marquis Changxing
is the least likely to betray my father.
Normally,
I could discuss things with him.
But unfortunately,
these days,
Mr. Chen is away on an assignment.
After much thought,
I could only
use Shuanghua as a pretext
to summon you here.
Whatever Your Highness commands,
I will spare no effort.
Your Highness,
what is this?
Inside is a map of the palace's
secret passages.
One end connects to the Eastern Palace,
and the other to the Imperial Garden.
I am telling you about the secret passages
just as a precaution.
If there ever comes
a time of true emergency,
I...
If that day ever comes,
even if it costs my life,
I will keep Your Highness safe.
Your Highness,
this is a letter from Guard Li.
She's back!
Your Highness.
I haven't seen you for months.
Your manners have become even worse.
How dare you
summon me here on a whim?
And you didn't even bow
when you saw me.
Qingpu,
watch outside.
Yes, my Lady.
I have something to tell you.
It's about your master,
Divine Doctor Xiao.
I don't believe it!
Totally nonsense!
There are plenty of people in the world
with the same handwriting.
Just because of a single note,
you concluded that he's Xiao Qishan!
And you falsely accused him of treason!
And I, for your sake,
specially invited him
to treat your mother!
You really know how to twist things!
Ye Xian,
listen to me.
I don't want to hear a single word!
My Lady,
we took a huge risk
and traveled all night
just to bring the news to His Highness.
How can he
be so ungrateful?
He grew up
with Divine Doctor Xiao.
They are like father and son.
It's normal that he can't accept it
right away.
But he is a smart man.
He should know
that I wouldn't lie.
[Baiwei Restaurant]
Young Master.
Did you hear all that?
Yes,
Young Master.
Do you believe it?
I am asking if you believe it!
Has Master truly
been deceiving me all these years?
I don't know.
But I don't think
Miss Gu would lie to you.
[Baiwei Restaurant]
It's said that
Xiao Qishan was the main instigator
behind the former Prince Chengqing's
uprising.
I didn't believe it back then.
But seeing
how he immediately defected
to Marquis Changxing
after the Prince's defeat,
I think the man is indeed a talent.
When I heard
this news,
I was also extremely shocked.
However,
based on the evidence gathered this time,
Prince Ruichang collaborated with
Xiao Qishan
and this is suspected of treason.
And Marquis Changxing.
Sir, what are your thoughts
on Marquis Changxing's involvement
in this?
With Xiao Qishan involved,
Marquis Changxing can't
escape responsibility.
Arrest him if necessary.
Do you want to protect Marquis Changxing?
Not exactly.
But Marquis Changxing
has outstanding military achievements
and immense prestige within the army.
If he's gone
and war breaks out again
at the Nine Border Garrisons,
we have to think carefully
about who could replace him.
Let's set aside the fact that
war is unlikely at
the Nine Border Garrisons for now.
The state treasury is abundant now.
Can't we train a few good soldiers?
Jiuheng,
you are exceptionally intelligent,
but you just lack some experience.
If you want to improve,
you need to
take the long view on everything.
Yes.
[Linxia Restaurant]
Third Master,
just as you expected,
Miss Gu rode fast to the capital
overnight after we left.
The first thing she did
was go see Young Master Ye.
[Linxia Restaurant]
Miss Gu.
You are back.
It's so good that you're back.
After you and Young Master Rong
went to Tongzhou,
Master's duty was suspended.
Master goes to the tavern
all day long,
caring about nothing.
Now, Miss Lan manages
everything big and small in the household.
These days,
even though you haven't been
in the residence,
I've instructed people
to clean your courtyard and Rong's daily.
You must be exhausted
from the long journey.
I have told the kitchen
to make some
longan and red date soup
to help you replenish energy.
Thank you for your trouble.
If you have something to say,
just say it.
I want to apologize to you.
These days,
I have thought it through.
In the past, I was blinded
by selfish motives,
unable to distinguish right from wrong
or loyalty from treachery.
I will never dare do it again.
Please, Zhao,
forgive my mistakes.
From now on,
I will listen to you for everything
and be at your command.
That doesn't sound like you
at all.
Get up.
What do you want?
You are so straightforward, Zhao.
Then
I'll be frank.
I heard that
before you left for Tongzhou,
you made a written agreement
with our father.
Concerning your marriage and Rong's...
Father is not allowed to interfere.
They are for you to decide.
I want to be like Rong
and you too.
In the future,
if our father
uses my marriage as a tool,
please lend me a hand.
You don't agree?
I don't agree to trade with you
simply because it's unnecessary.
I don't need you
to listen to me for everything.
And I don't wish to
interfere in your marriage either.
It seems
you still haven't forgiven me.
Never mind.
More words are useless.
Time will tell.
My Lady,
do you think Miss Lan
is telling the truth or not?
Who cares if it's true or not?
But based on what I know about her,
it's mostly likely true.
Actually, sometimes I think
she is quite pitiful.
Unlike me,
she doesn't have a grandmother to rely on.
Now
she only has herself.
I wonder
how Ye Xian is doing now.
[Marquis Changxing's Mansion]
Greetings, Your Highness.
Is Master Xiao here?
Your Highness,
Mr. Xiao and the Marquis
have gone to discuss matters.
I bribed the night soil collector.
He sneaked into the manor to take a look.
There are two full chests
of sharpened swords and spears,
as well as smoke bombs.
They are all military standard.
It seems
your previous deduction was right.
Prince Ruichang has
treacherous intentions
and grand ambitions.
Indeed.
It seems my guess was correct.
It is indeed Your Highness.
Since you are here,
come in.
Father, are you discussing matters
with Master?
Maybe
I should come back later.
No need.
You've grown up.
The Marquis's Mansion
will eventually be handed over to you.
Come in and listen to
our discussion today.
Come in.
Prince Ruichang is secretly
buying weapons.
How did you know?
Unbeknownst to you,
I have had Mr. Xiao
secretly monitoring
Prince Ruichang's residence.
These days, Prince Ruichang has been close
to Yun Tao,
the Northern City Military Commander,
and Lu Ming,
Commander of the Imperial Golden Guard.
He's having frequent contact with them.
Last month,
he even gave Commander Yun
two beauties from the Western Regions.
I've talked too much.
No amount of water helps.
I remember
you didn't talk much before.
Before, we were in the mountains.
Besides you little brat,
there were only monkeys.
There was nothing to talk about.
Why are you staring at me like that?
You secretly helped my father
spy on Prince Ruichang's Mansion.
It's such a big matter.
Why have you been hiding it from me?
I didn't mean to hide it from you.
I just thought you were still young,
so there was no need to tell you.
Why are you in such a hurry
to find me?
Gu Jinzhao...
Gu Jinzhao has returned from Tongzhou.
I want to go see her.
I don't want to go empty-handed,
but I also don't want
to bring her some boring common gifts.
So I was wondering
if you have anything good
worthy of giving.
What good things
could I possibly have here?
Bows and arrows?
Daggers?
Or hidden weapons?
Poison?
I just made this slingshot.
Take it if you want.
I don't want this.
I just thought of the slingshot
you gave me back then.
Did I give you a slingshot?
Yes.
That year when I returned to the capital,
I was only there for a day
before I wrote you to come pick me up.
From the first day of the New Year,
I waited until the Lantern Festival.
You were finally here.
Ye Xian.
Master!
What's wrong?
[Youth Ye Xian]
Why are you unhappy?
Look at what I brought you.
I don't want a slingshot.
I want a crossbow.
You are still too young.
I promise you.
When you grow up a bit,
I will definitely give you a crossbow.
It's a deal.
You have a really good memory.
I don't remember that at all.
Take this slingshot.
Never mind.
I'll find something else.
This kid
is acting quite strange today.
Your Highness.
I'm here to see your young lady.
How is it?
You guessed it right.
Someone is indeed following.
You finally believe
what I said?
Yes.
I was afraid of arousing suspicion.
So I could only use the excuse
of returning Baopu to come see you.
Is there a side door in your residence?
I need to see Chen Yanyun.
The sooner, the better.
On the north side of our mansion,
there is a small door.
It leads directly to an alley
and is very well-hidden.
I'll take you there now.
Master Xiao
told me in front of my father
that Prince Ruichang was secretly
hoarding weapons
and secretly
conspiring with
the Northern City Military Commander
and the Imperial Golden Guard.
The way I see it,
it seems like he's helping my father
guard against Prince Ruichang's rebellion.
I believe Zhao wouldn't lie to me.
But if that's the case,
Xiao You essentially
told my father everything.
This situation...
I find it confusing.
Could it be that
Xiao You didn't betray Marquis Changxing?
But those weapons...
Why did he transport them
to Prince Ruichang?
What confuses me most is that
Xiao You, on one hand, has my father
guard against Prince Ruichang,
yet on the other hand,
he secretly works for Prince Ruichang.
What is he after?
The Marquis is extremely loyal
to the Great Yan.
He hates traitors the most.
When the Prince Chengqing rebelled,
it was the Marquis
who cut him down with one stroke.
Now,
if the Marquis knows Prince Ruichang
has the intention to rebel,
how could he just sit and wait?
He will definitely gather troops secretly
and get ready to protect the Emperor
at any time.
But if so,
the Marquis's actions
might become evidence
of his own future rebellion.
This
is probably what Xiao You is after.
Right now, the Marquis's Mansion
is in a hopeless situation.
If Prince Ruichang rebels,
the Marquis will definitely
lead troops into the palace
to protect His Majesty.
Not to act
would be equivalent to treason.
But to act
would also be deemed treason.
Third Master,
is there any way to break this deadlock?
There is a way,
but it's extremely dangerous.
[A Splendid Match]